# Juan Sebastián Puerta Ordóñez

Colombia | +57 314 608 6847 <u>Email | LinkedIn | Github</u>

### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I am a computer scientist with more than two years of experience in frontend and backend web development. I have worked with languages like Python, JavaScript and C, and I have solid knowledge in modern frameworks like Svelte and React for creating dynamic and efficient interfaces. On the backend, I have experience integrating services and handling relational and non-relational databases such as MySQL and MongoDB respectively. I am fluent in GNU/Linux operating systems, which allows me to easily work in development and production environments.

I consider myself a collaborative, friendly and team-oriented person. I enjoy participating in projects where I can contribute ideas, learn from others and create solutions that generate impact.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer Engineer | VitralAI | Manizales, Colombia

2024 - Currently

- Maintain and optimize a backend composed of microservices developed in Python.
- Implement technologies such as gRPC for inter-service communication, MongoDB for database management and Redis for caching and session management.
- Assist in the implementation of new functionalities in the frontend, which is in JavaScript using the Svelte framework.

Software System Engineer | Salto del Mortiño | Popayán, Colombia

2023 - 2024

- Develop a system for sending automatic messages to customers.
- Maintaining and updating a relational database in MySQL.
- Manage and maintain financial and personnel accounts.

Software Developer (Internship) | ISA Intercolombia | Medellín, Colombia

2022 - 2023

Develop a system for automatic prioritization of power tower maintenance review. This system was done in Python using cloud technology provided by Azure.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Software Systems Engineer** | ICESI University | Cali, Colombia

2017 - 2022

# **Knowledge:**

- Advanced knowledge: Python, JavaScript, Github
- ❖ Intermediate knowledge: C, HTML, CSS, React, Svelte, GNU/Linux
- Basic knowledge: Google Cloud, Azure, AWS

## Languages:

Spanish: Native

English: B1 - ICESI University